Evan English

Address: 107 St. Brendans Rd, Farranree, Co. Cork, Ireland Contact Number: 0851527836 Email Address: evan@evane123.com

Summary

Confident, friendly, and hardworking individual. Experienced technical specialists with a demonstrated history of work in the computer software industry. Strong background in front facing customer service roles, technical troubleshooting, training & computer science.

Very well organized with a keen attention to detail. Devoted to achieving my goals and intent on learning new skills. Works well within a team and in a solo environment, with experience in both fields. Passionate about problem solving and helping others.

Skills/Hobbies

General

- · Technical troubleshooting
- · Computer Architecture
- · Web design & Web architecture
- · Web & Software development
- · Logical/Critical thinking
- · Communications skills
- · Excellent customer relations skills
- · Logical/Critical thinking
- Capable of taking initiative and works well without instruction or supervision

Programming Language experience

- · HTML5/CSS/Twitter Bootstrap/Vue.js
- · JavaScript/JQuery
- Python
- \cdot Go(Lang)
- · JAVA
- \cdot MySQL

Education

May 2013 FETAC

FETAC Level 5 Certificate (Information Technology), Central Technical Institute Clonmel

Experience

March 2019 -Present

Technical Specialist. *Teamwork*

- Compiling, calculating and delivering multi-products reports and metrics to drive internal reporting and trend analysis.
- Delivering API and Technical Training to customer facing teams.
- · Handling API support queries & maintaining customer Developer portal.
- Testing and identifying custom-built integrations for potential release to customers, ensuring data privacy standards are met.
- Educate and enable support agents in more technical aspects of Product issues.
- · In-depth testing, and analysis of bug reports to identify root causes.
- Provide internal support to Engineering, Technical Services, Sales and other departments in the best interests of the customer experience.
- Designing and implementing internal efficiency workflows using custom scripts to drive automation throughout the support department.
- Working closely with development teams on feature enhancements and bug fixes through design specs and testing.
- Maintaining quality assurance and accuracy of API Documentation for both internal and external use.
- · Handling and executing GDPR related Data purge requests.
- · Assisting operations teams in visitor management programs and setting up check-in portals/notification systems for multiple offices.

Jan 2018 - Feb 2019

Customer Support Specialist, Teamwork

- Delivering timely, friendly and comprehensive customer support
- · Technical troubleshooting
- Supporting others on the team via help with bug reports, ticket answering and troubleshooting.
- · Detailed bug testing and logging

July 2016 -December 2018

Escalation Manager - G Suite by Google Cloud, Voxpro

- Compiling Monthly/Quarterly metrics for internal assessments.
- · Monthly/Quarterly Business Reviews
- Taking full management of front facing communication with clients.
- Monitoring trends, Priority issues and advice of improvement paths to prevent re-occurrence.
- Maintaining continuous communication with clients and all parties involved in the escalation.
- · Quality Reviews and coaching of Technical Support agents.
- · Hands on work with Salesforce Reporting.
- Updating and maintaining internal documentations and workflows.

April 2015 - July 2016

G Suite by Google Cloud Technical Support, Voxpro

- · Technical Support at a high level (Phone/Email)
- Hitting monthly targets
- · Providing excellent customer service and experiences
- Engaging in monthly team meetings with Product Engineers to discuss common issues to better enhance the product and support offered.